本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 小坏玩意儿不坏 虾饺女神锦鲤
校对： 想念虾饺的阿南   后期： 想念虾饺的阿南
舞蹈学院 前情提要
Previously on Dance Academy...
你要上台去演珀尔塞福涅
You need to go on stage as Persephone.
如果你发挥出自己的水平
And if you dance it the way I know you can
你的前途将会一片光明
your future is written in the stars.
塔拉 你还好吗 你还好吗
Tara, you OK? You OK?
- 你会没事的 - 塔拉
- You're going to be fine. - Tara?
舞蹈学院 第三季第13集
我整夜未眠
I've been up all night.
可惜合同需要今天签订 所以这是最后的机会
Unfortunately the contracts need to go out today so this is the last opportunity.
我无法恨她
I can't hate her.
如果我都不能振作起来
How am I supposed to compete with her
我该怎么和她竞争
if I can't even muster up a shred...
为另一种原因而跳舞
Dance for a different reason.
变化无处不在
So often change is incremental,
你甚至不会注意到的细小转折
tiny turning points you don't even notice.
还有其他的变故
Then there are other events -
突然的 巨大的 决定性的
sudden, monumental, defining -
改变你的一生
that change you forever.
在你投出骰子的一霎那
And in that split second after you've thrown the dice,
结局已经注定 然而你迫切想要改变
it could go one way but you desperately want it to go another,
让前途不再悬而未决
where your future is suspended in limbo,
你会乞求吗
do you beg?
会讨价还价吗
Do you bargain?
希望 祈祷还是威胁
Wish? Pray? Threaten?
抗争到底还是放任自流
Do you fight or let go?
是否绝望时才能看清自己 知道自己的能量
Is it only in limbo that you finally know yourself and what you're capable of?
塔拉摔倒时 她有缺陷的脊椎另一侧
When Tara fell, the other side of her defective vertebra
- 折断并错位 - 需要多久才能康复
- snapped and slipped forward. - How long will it take, recovery?
去年我受伤时休息了八周
Last year when I broke it I was out for eight weeks
如果我有幸拿到合约 就得尽快恢复
and if I'm lucky enough to get a contract I'll have to start work soon.
咱们先让你站起来
Let's focus on getting you back on your feet.
这是开放性手术
It's an open operation,
意味着需要切开塔拉的腹部
which means they'll go through Tara's abdomen
插入铁丝箍 替换椎间盘
and insert a wire cage which will replace the disc.
格瑞斯
Grace.
抱歉 听起来
Sorry. Um, that all sounds -
是从一月开始吗
is it January I start?
我打算去越南过圣诞节
I've got this Christmas in Vietnam fantasy plan.
事实上 我说的是
Actually, what I was leading to...
我们这次不打算和你签约
We've decided not to offer you a contract this time.
很显然你才华横溢
Obviously you are a tremendous talent
但我的原则是和谐的环境
but my philosophy is that a harmonious environment
比个别舞蹈演员的资格
is more conducive to creating good work
更利于创造好的作品
than the quality of the individual dancers.
你是说我和别人不和
You're saying I don't play nicely with others,
还是你不想和我合作
or that you don't want to work with me.
还是两者兼有
Or both.
她是前任冠军
She's the pre-champion.
传言说我们都不会拿到合约
Rumours about none of us getting contracts -
越来越可信了
gaining credibility.
你确定没有任何问题了吗
You sure you don't have any questions?
好的
Alright, then.
你先睡一会儿
We'll get you nicely to sleep.
几个小时后再见
You'll see us in a few hours.
想倒数十个数吗
Want to count us in from 10?
十 九
10, 9,
八 七
8, 7,
六 五
6, 5,
四 三
4, 3...
你快迟到了吧
Aren't you late for class?
不能穿这身去啊
You can't wear that.
我不知道自己在做什么
I don't really know what I'm doing.
你应该知道
Well, you should.
这是你的潜意识
It's your subconscious.
来吧
Come on.
你为什么对医生说你没有问题
Why did you tell the doctor you didn't have any questions?
我觉得是个大问题
I'd call it a fairly big one.
如果手术不成功你再也不能跳舞了怎么办
What if the surgery doesn't work and you can never dance again?
因为它必须成功 我不能经历这些然后一无所得
Because it has to work. I can't have come all this way for nothing.
真的 你确定
Really? You sure about that?
我们都是忠实粉丝
We're all big fans.
你技术扎实 有成为领舞的勇气
You have the technical facility and the courage of a leading man.
领舞 天哪
Leading man. Wow.
过奖了
If you say so.
可是我们舞团已经有几个
The difficulty is we already have several dancers of your type
你这样的舞者
in the company.
我希望奉行个人主义
I want to push things to be more individualistic.
我的类型很多变
My type's totally fluid.
你们想要什么样的我都能胜任
I can be whoever you want me to be.
我真的很抱歉 本
I'm really very sorry, Ben.
塔拉 你的阿拉贝斯克舞姿腿不够高
Tara, those arabesques are still too low.
如果你背部不适 就别练了
If your back is straining, please sit this out.
我没事 抱歉 瑞贝卡
I'm fine. Sorry, Rebecca.
所以 我进了舞团 我拿到合约了
So, I'm in the company. I get a contract.
我怎么知道 我又不能预测未来
How would I know? I don't have access to the future.
但是的 在这个版本的现实中你在跳舞
But, yes, in this version of reality you're dancing.
不全是独角兽和三叶草 对吧
It's not all unicorns and clovers, is it?
看上去真疼
That looks youchy.
为了什么
And for what?
你甚至不想进舞团
You didn't even like being in the corps.
常年的批评 永远做不到最好
Constant criticism. Never being good enough.
我打赌如果你再不能跳舞你会有些释怀
I bet part of you will be relieved if you can't dance again.
但这是我梦寐以求的
But this is all I've ever wanted.
你同意 牺牲是值得的
You agree. The sacrifice is worth it.
血压怎么样
How's our BP looking?
- 她是不是 - 血压升高
- Is she becoming... - ..hypertensive?
情况不太好
I don't like the swelling.
你得帮我拿到和马库斯的面试
You've got to get me that audition with Marcus.
本 你在仓促做决定
Ben, you're scrambling.
奥斯汀甚至都挤不进你的前五个选择
Austin didn't even make your top five.
你说的没错 这真是"学院血案"
And you're right. It's a bloodbath.
- 我坚持了四年 就是为了...  - ...一无所获
- Four years. All for... - ...absolutely nothing.
里德 有戏吗
Reed, care to share with the group?
教芭蕾是没法招到学生的 老大
You're not gonna get any kids with ballet boss.
那又如何
So?
拜托 我自己的工作面试我都没这么激动
Come on. I wasn't even this worked up on my own interview day.
- 他们把时间改成今天下午了 - 扶着另外一边
- They changed it to this afternoon. - Grab the other end.
正式确定了吗
Does this make it official?
由你来管舞蹈中心
You running the centre.
我跟我老婆说 都怪你
I told my wife to blame you.
其他东西我都不懂
How I'm going to fit it in with everything else
- 我怎么管理这个地方 - 这件事值得你去做
- I do not know. - It's worth it.
至少在未来会有意义 如果你从教小孩子们街舞开始
At least it's going to be. If you start the kids off with hip hop
慢慢过渡到教芭蕾
and drip-feed them ballet later.
我都分不清嘻哈和锁舞啊
I wouldn't recognise a pop from a lock.
更别说你跳的那些什么椅子舞
Let alone those armchair things you do.
你跳得不错啊
That was good.
但是你双脚的位置要一直保持在臀部以下 准备好了吗
But keep your feet underneath your bum at all times. Ready?
好吧 好吧
Yep. Yep.
是啊 我知道
No, I know.
但是要等到肿胀消退了
They can't even give us a prognosis on her walking
医生才能告诉我们 塔拉能否再站起来
until the swelling goes down.
我们已经把你拍电影的事儿告诉老家的每一个人啦
We've been telling everyone at home young Kat's in a movie.
呃 我只是运气很好
Uh, I got pretty lucky.
尼尔 抱歉 我走开一下
Sorry, Neil, excuse me for a second.
她怎么样了
How is she?
有什么新消息吗
Any news?
最新消息是 她可能要坐轮椅了
The update is she might be in a wheelchair.
那你来这又是想干嘛 来炫耀你得到了合约
And you're here to... what? Gloat about getting a contract?
我没得到合约
I didn't get a contract.
昨晚塔拉说 她怀念我们还是朋友的时候
Last night Tara said she missed us being friends.
我本以为我希望这样的事情发生 但实际上我不想
I thought I wanted something like this to happen but I didn't.
我一点也不愿意她变成这样
At all.
我能再来一遍吗
Can I go again?
今天发生了不少事情
It's been a big day.
多事之秋
Big year.
我能跳得更好的
I can do it better.
每所芭蕾院校都把舞团视为根基
Every ballet school puts their company up on a pedestal
好像只有身在舞团 凡事才有意义
as though they're the only place worth anything.
可是没让你们做好落选的准备
They don't prepare you for this.
你感到失望 也是理所应当
You're allowed to feel disappointed.
什么叫"情况复杂"
What sort of complications?
她目前情况稳定 但是这个手术难度较大
She's stable. But it's a very delicate operation.
手术还需要些时间
It's going to take some more time.
那到底还需要多久呢
How much more time?
很抱歉 我得走了 我得去参加一个演出 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I've got to go. I've got a performance. I'm so sorry.
没事儿
OK.
- 手术会有什么其他风险吗 - 不会
- Will there be any additional risk? - No additional risk.
她的确有些...
She does have...
凯特 情况稳定意味着她会好起来的
Kat. Stable means she's going to be OK.
这跟山姆的情况不一样 相信我 好吗
This isn't a Sammy situation. OK?
别想太多
Come on.
我去替你
I'll take you over.
可能是我们自己看问题的方式不对
Maybe we're just looking at this the wrong way.
这家舞团现在当家的是个初出茅庐的总监
I mean, the company is an organisation in turmoil,
舞团陷于混乱中 随时可能垮台
poised to explode with an inexperienced director at the helm.
除此之外 我是群舞演员
And besides, corps de ballet -
还是说我们有独舞机会呢
is it just me or are we soloist standard?
要我说也该是首席舞者
I'd say principals.
我们来做个约定 就现在
We should make a pact. Now.
如果咱俩中只有一个被选进舞团
If either of us gets in...
我们也要拒绝
we still say no.
我无心打扰
Not to interrupt.
不过你可以进来面试了 奥利弗
We're ready for you, Oliver.
你给我乖乖在后排当半年伴舞
Just back row of the corps for two seasons
如果我发现你有一点点耍个性...
and if I get one whiff of ego out of you...
只要你要求 我就乖乖做个有脉搏的道具
I'll be a prop with a pulse if you ask me to.
第二个场景
Exhibit B
让你考虑清楚
for your consideration.
你总是压抑自己不去享受生活
You've always pretzelled yourself
而是全身心投入芭蕾
over the ballet versus life equation.
而这就是 你的生活中没有舞蹈的样子
This is what happens if you remove dancing altogether.
什么嘛 我们全都没有工作 就在山上晃悠
What? We're all unemployed and hanging out on the hill?
不是啦 是零压力
No pressure.
没竞争
No competition.
还有和你想象中一样多的爱恋情节
As many crushes as your little heart fancies.
最重要的是 我们明年还可以呆在一起
Plus, we could stay together next year.
我也不确定 就算这样 我觉得我还是需要坚持梦想 证明自己
I don't know. Even then I think I still need a dream to define me.
我就猜到你会这么说
Kind of knew you'd say that.
距离国立舞蹈学院 剧目葛蓓莉亚开演还有十分钟
The National Academy's performance of Coppelia will commence in 10 minutes.
你一般很难接受被拒这种事啊
You don't normally cope this well with rejection.
我一直等着这次打击呢
I'm waiting for it to hit me.
或者说 我已经被打击了 只是我不在乎
Or maybe it already has and I just don't care.
因为你可以去任何地方 留在任何一个舞团啊
'Cause you can go anywhere and dance with any company.
不是跳舞 而是找到自己真正想做的事
Not dance, find something I actually care about.
嗨 我最好的朋友正在做脊椎手术
Hey, my best friend's having spinal surgery
而我则一直希望能有一个人对我说
and I keep hoping someone's going to say,
凯特 你今晚不用登台
'Kat, you don't have to dance tonight.'
不过这是到目前为止 我舞蹈生涯的巅峰了
To date, this is the high point of my dancing life
不过只要能不去跳 什么奇葩理由我都可以找
and I'll take any horrific excuse not to do it.
没准你跟我很像
You could also be like me.
最开始你也不是一门心思想投身舞蹈
You never really wanted this in the first place,
你只是觉得你应该这么做
you just decided you should want it.
克里斯提 你得走了
Christian, you got to go.
没事儿 不急
It's cool.
听我的 这次会面你不该迟到
Trust me. This is not an appointment you can be late for.
你开玩笑的吧 对不对
You're kidding, right?
你在跟我开玩笑 哈
You're kidding. Ha.
我早说过你会得到合约的 是不是
I told you, didn't I?
我希望你能替我保管
I want you to keep it.
我不能那么做 这是你的合约啊 你得把它签了
I can't. It's a contract. You've got to sign it.
噢 不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
你不能逃避 至少这一次不行
You are not walking away. Not this time.
我想留在这里工作 我想教课
I want to work here. I want to teach.
那你就在舞团待个十年 然后出来当老师啊
So do ten years in the company then be a teacher.
我终于找到了自己想做的事情
I finally know what I want to do.
而我要从现在开始做了
And I want to start doing it.
所以... 一人分饰双角来救场
So... dance double to the rescue.
可以这么说
Something like that.
快跟我说说 他喜欢你 是不是
So, come on. He loved you, right?
说实话我不清楚
I honestly couldn't tell.
不过我喜欢马库斯 奥斯汀也不错
But I like Marcus. Austin could be good.
刚才一路跑过来我都在想...
And running over here I just kept thinking...
这一整年你都在当我最好的朋友
You've been my best friend this whole year
而我也想和你一起度过下一年
I don't want to spend the next one without you.
我不能去
I can't go.
不能去奥斯汀
To Austin.
我有太多要做的事情
I've got so much stuff to work out.
我能帮你啊
I can help.
我很擅长处理事情 所以...
I'm good with stuff so...
我的软肋就是把某人当成全世界 然后因此憎恨他们
My MO is making someone my whole world and then hating them for it.
而我不想恨你
I don't want to hate you.
我知道目前的状况 但我...
I understand in the circumstances but I am...
凯特帮了我一个大忙
Kat did me an amazing favour.
她让我明白 如果我要和芭蕾分手
I figured if I was saying goodbye to ballet
我希望完美地谢幕
I wanted to make it a good one.
格瑞斯
Grace.
艾比盖尔 没关系的 我理解
Abigail, it's OK. Really.
很抱歉我现在得走了 我晚上有约了
I'm sorry but I do have a dinner that I have to get to.
四年勤练舞 终得一纸约
I just worked so hard.
你干嘛带我来这儿
Why would you take me here?
这是因为...
Because, trust me.
当有噩耗发生
When the bad stuff happens
你不能被它们牵着鼻子走
you can't let it drag you down.
你不能随着它改变你
You can't let it change you.
这不是你真正的目的
That's not the real reason.
你的路数太逊了 我不会让你得逞的
This is a cheap stunt, I'm not going to let you manipulate me.
那好 你来告诉我 我们为什么来这儿
Alright. Tell me. Why do you think we're here?
因为...
Because...
因为我看不见他
because I can't see him.
就算过了这么久 我还是那么想见他
Even now, and I so want to see him.
我知道他永远离开我们了
I know he's gone.
山姆不在了
Sammy died.
他的梦想都还没实现
He didn't get his dream.
甚至没有机会重新找到一个梦想
He didn't even get the possibility of finding a new one.
但我活在当下
And I'm alive.
嗨
Hi.
你不是该去跳葛蓓莉亚了吗
Coppelia?
小塔 别担心那个 我想要待在你的身边
T, don't worry about that. I'm where I want to be.
但你是领舞啊
You're the lead.
现在对我来说 领舞也不是那么重要了
It didn't matter so much in the end.
待会再跟你解释 我得去找你爸妈了
I'll explain later. I've got to go get your Mum and Dad.
我的脚趾 它们还能...
My toes, are they...
即使我已经决定接受这一切
So even though I'd decided I wouldn't feel sorry for myself
复健却不像是在公园里散步那么简单
rehab wasn't a walk in the park.
实际上 我再也不会把在公园散步当做理所当然了
In fact, I'd never take walking in a park for granted again.
更不用说跳舞
Much less dancing.
我要努力拼搏 找回自我
I'm going to fight as hard as I can to get back to where I was.
不过如果事与愿违
But if that doesn't happen
我再也不能成为职业舞者
and I never dance professionally
我也可以坦然接受
I know I'll still be OK.
艾比 这就是你最好的水平了吗
Abby, call that 100%?
无懈可击的你呢
Where's your turnout?
我是凯特・卡拉马科夫 我来试镜二号女招待的角色
Kat Karamakov testing for the role of waitress number two.
我很抱歉 请无视我
I'm sorry. Pretend that didn't happen.
当初我来到舞蹈学院 努力成为最好的芭蕾舞者
I came to the academy to be the best ballerina I could be
但我丢失了勇气
but what I took away was courage,
失去了驻足停留的勇气 对着空白页
to stop and wonder at the blank page,
或宽阔的道路思索的勇气
the open road,
拥有雄心和壮志的勇气
to dream big but also wide,
随时准备拥有新的梦想
allowing room for new dreams,
不期而遇的梦想
unexpected ones.
因为最重要的不在于实现梦想
Because the point never was achieving the dream,
而是要心怀梦想 并为之倾尽全力
it was having one and pouring everything into it.
稍等一会 他还在上课
Hang on a sec. I think he's still teaching a class.
杰登 如果你连衣服都不拉好
Jayden, how am I supposed to correct you
我要怎么纠正你的动作呢
if you don't pull up your tights?
永远不知道将来会发生什么 这一点很有趣
It's funny, I have no idea what happens next.
不过能用自己的方式活出精彩
But I'm excited about finding my own way
我也乐在其中
to make it count,
山姆就是这样
the way Sammy did.
在这里 每个人都能拥有梦想 尽情起舞
He would have loved this space
他也一定会爱上这里的
where anyone can dream and dance.
现在我宣布 舞蹈中心正式成立啦
I now declare it officially open.
这还未成书 我也确信它绝对不会出版
It's not a book yet and I'm pretty sure it won't get published
但里面全是关于我们和舞蹈学院
but it's about us and the academy.
好了 小伙伴们 这里就是用来跳舞的
OK, guys. This place is about dancing.
那我们就来一段吧
So, how about we do some?
有一阵子了 跟我说说吧
Been a while. Tell me about it.
我简直不敢相信... 你是怎么编排出这段舞的
I can't believe - how did you all organise this?
这是献给你的舞蹈
This is a thank you dance.
虽然迟了点 总比没有强
Better late than never.
一起来吧 这还是你的点子呢
Come on. This was your idea.
我一个月之前才上过第一节课呢
I only did my first class a month ago.
我们慢慢来
We'll take it slow.
我们与你同在
We'll figure it out together.
在我小时候
When I was young,
我不太明白重力这回事
I wasn't so clear on the whole gravity thing.
而我那天马行空的想象力让我吃了不少苦头
And my imagination got me in a lot of trouble.
但我记得有这么一刻
But I remember there was this one moment
时间仿佛静止
where time stopped
万物犹如有灵
and everything made sense.
从那时起 我就深知在另一个平行时空
From then on, I've always known that in another life
我可以飞翔
I could fly.
所以此生
And that's why in this life
我献给舞蹈
I dance.